Sometimes big things that happen in life make our body feel tired like we have butterflies in our stomach.
This exercise can help your body feel more normal if you feel like that.
It might feel a little funny at first, but with practice you get better and no one will even notice you're doing it.
For PMR we are tricking your muscles.
First, we make them very tight like when you feel stressed.
Then we make them very relaxed.
Start by sitting comfortably in your chair.
Put both feet on the floor and let your arms hang down.
You can close your eyes if it helps you relax.
Try to notice how your whole body feels right now.
Now, while sitting, pretend you will get a million dollars if you push hard with your legs.
Hold the push for 10 seconds.
Ready, set, go.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Now, relax your legs.
Let's try it again.
This time push with your legs and make your hands go into fists and squeeze them tight at the same time.
Ready.
Remember, one million dollars.
Go.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
You did great.
Shake your legs and wiggle your fingers.
PMR is something you can do for any part of your body that feels tight.
Your counselor can help you learn how to do it.